A Guide to the Opie Percival Read Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #9279-a
Opie Percival Read Collection 1885-1917
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
9279-a
8 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [ 1963 Dec 17 ] 1971 Jan 12
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Opie Percival Read to "Dear Sir", 1885 Oct 1; ALS, 1 p.
    [Includes magazine photo of Read; accompanies a sketch; indicates his preference for the correspondent's syndicate.]
  - Opie Percival Read to [Samuel Sidney] McClure, 1885 Nov 18; ALS, 1 p.
    [Accompanies a story submitted for publication; requests payment of $35 and attests to the truth of its characterization; requests information on McClure's syndicate to be published in his periodical.]
  - Opie Percival Read to [ I. D. Marshall], 1891 Dec 21; ALS, 1 p.
    [Discusses his interest in writing a short story weekly for syndication; expresses belief that the
    [Chicago] Tribune
    and the Batcheller papers would be interested.]
  - Opie Percival Read to S[amuel] S[idney] McClure, 1892 Jul 8; ALS, 1 p.
    [Wishes to submit short stories and sketches for publication.]
  - Opie Percival Read to [ I. D. Marshall], 1893 Feb 17; ALS, 1 p.
    [Accompanies a Decoration Day story; assures him that he is getting his money's worth.]
  - Opie Percival Read to [William Gerard] Chapman, 1917 Feb 13; ALS, 1 p.
    [Requests that a time be scheduled to talk over "the subject of your letter."]
  - Opie Percival Read to [William Gerard] Chapman, 1917 Oct 2; ALS, 1 p.
    [Indicates that no carbon copy was made of manuscript but proof sheets would be furnished; expresses gratitude that his work was pleasing.]
- Prints
  - Magazine Photograph, Opie Percival Read, head and shoulders, 1885 Oct 1; Photo